Dying to show you a good time.
X is a horror, thriller film directed by Ti West.
In 1979, a group of young filmmakers set out to make an adult film in rural Texas, but when their
reclusive, elderly hosts catch them in the act, the cast find themselves fighting for their lives.
Maxine / Pearl, played by Mia Goth.
Lorraine, played by Jenna Ortega.
Bobby-Lynne, played by Brittany Snow.
Jackson, played by Kid Cudi.
Wayne, played by Martin Henderson.
RJ, played by Owen Campbell.
X is a 2022 American slasher film written,
directed, produced and edited by Ti West.
It stars Mia Goth in dual roles: a young woman named
Maxine and an elderly woman named Pearl.
The film also stars Jenna Ortega, Martin Henderson, Brittany
Snow, Owen Campbell, Stephen Ure, and Scott Mescudi.
Set in 1979, the film follows a cast and crew who gather to make a pornographic film on an elderly
couple's rural Texas property but find themselves threatened by the homicidal couple.
A24 announced X in November 2020.
Principal photography occurred in February–March
2021, primarily in Fordell, New Zealand.
Goth underwent extensive prosthetic makeup for Pearl, and special
effects were employed to depict violent scenes in the film.
Characterized as a contemporary take on psycho-biddy, X draws inspiration from horror, exploitation, and
pornographic films, and emphasizes the interplay between beauty, aging, and self-worth.
The score was composed by Tyler Bates and Chelsea Wolfe.
X had its world premiere at South by Southwest on March 13, 2022, and was
theatrically released in the United States five days later by A24.
It received generally positive reviews from critics.
It is the first installment of the X film series, followed by the prequel film
Pearl (September 2022) and the sequel MaXXXine (July 2024).
The film explores themes of van, pornography, sheriff, war veteran, gas station.
The tone is dark and intense.